<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VibeCoder</title><link>https://vibhasgoyal.com/</link><description>Recent content on VibeCoder</description><generator>Hugo 0.125.0</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vibhasgoyal.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About</title><link>https://vibhasgoyal.com/page/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vibhasgoyal.com/page/about/</guid><description>Hi, I am Vibhas Goyal aka VibeCoder. Simple tech enthusiast, Programmer
Currently working as Senior Member of Technical Staff at Oracle. Working on the Oracle Analytics team.
I studied from B.Tech (2014 - 2018) in Engineering Science and Computer Science from IIT Hyderabad.
Ideas Behind this Blog and its purpose I truly hope that you may get some practical information from this website that help you and that is my mission regarding this website.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://vibhasgoyal.com/page/contact/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 20:24:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://vibhasgoyal.com/page/contact/</guid><description>Please contact me at vibecoderdev@gmail.com
📫 How to reach me: &amp;hellip;
https://dev.to/vibecoder https://github.com/vibecoder https://twitter.com/vibecoder https://twitch.tv/vibecoder https://ko-fi.com/vibecoder https://www.patreon.com/vibecoder https://discord.gg/FhujpH33xE https://www.youtube.com/@vibecoderdev</description></item><item><title>Tweets</title><link>https://vibhasgoyal.com/tweets/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vibhasgoyal.com/tweets/</guid><description>Interestingly enough people who don&amp;rsquo;t have touch typing skills use passwords that are suited to type with just one finger.
Keep your ears free. No music. No videos. No podcasts.Try it. Will this finally make me insane.
A great productivity hack. Pause before you click on anything. Be mindful of what you are reading</description></item><item><title>My health in late 20s</title><link>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/my-health-in-late-20s/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/my-health-in-late-20s/</guid><description>You know what everyone in their 30s say right.
Oh my back has suddenly started to pain.
Oh my knees are paining.
Oh my chest is tightening.
My jaw is aching.
Yep, that is me now. Every body part starts to pain.
I am getting old. And I will have to learn to accept this fact.
Time is ticking old man.
I just want a little more strength now.
I know this is a somewhat weird thing to post.</description></item><item><title>Samsung R&amp;D Bangalore Interview Experience</title><link>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/samsung-interview/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/samsung-interview/</guid><description>Samsung really was the worst interview experience.
One day, I suddenly get a call from a recruiter based on my profile from Naukri.com
On the call, the recruiter basically just asked me directly when I would like to have the interview.
I was initially impressed that they decided to move it fast but this feeling did not last long..
Immediately I got an invite for the interview.
I looked at it.</description></item><item><title>LeetCode 1658</title><link>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/leetcode-1658/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/leetcode-1658/</guid><description>A simple problem on the first approach that I have to look at.
Let&amp;rsquo;s see this as two pointers.
One starting from the index 0 and the other index will start from len-1.
int begin = 0 ; int end = len - 1; If there is no solution we return -1
return -1; This will track the number of edits
int count = 0; The first step is to check if arr[begin] is less than arr[end],</description></item><item><title>NVIM</title><link>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/nvim/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/nvim/</guid><description>Nvim is the best editor so far. But we have to configure it.
Otherwise, it&amp;rsquo;s just a text editor.
The one down side I found is that it cannot be used very effectively over ssh.
Usually the VM&amp;rsquo;s are not configured like the way nvim is done locally.
So not a good idea to use it?
Nah, still it is so smooth and fast to use it as if this is the only thing that has made editing my files as fast as my thoughts.</description></item><item><title>Keychron K8 Pro</title><link>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/keychron-k8-pro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/keychron-k8-pro/</guid><description>Why a new keyboard? I brought this keyboard because I have been looking forward to owning a proper mechanical keyboard again for some time now.
The last proper keyboard I had was the ErgoDox EZ.
It was a good keyboard.
But this is even better I think.
QMK / VIA configuration. This was a bit confusing at first. It still is but I have made some changes to suit my needs.</description></item><item><title>My journey of switching code editors</title><link>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/archive/shifting-to-nvim/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/archive/shifting-to-nvim/</guid><description>So sometime back , I decided to switch to the latest hotshot meme that I witnessed.
I was casually browsing Twitch, bored out of my mind looking for something fun.
I for a random reason decided to search for &amp;ldquo;Software&amp;rdquo; and I saw the primeagen streaming..
A goofball coder with Dr Disrespect asthetics. But also works at Netflix and has a solid knowledge of what he is doing with the code.</description></item><item><title>Learning Rust</title><link>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/archive/rust/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/archive/rust/</guid><description>First of all, rust is totally new to me.
I do not understand what it is trying to resolve.
First thing that I have learned is that ..
The if statements do not need the paranenthesis. Shows up a weird warning. Should not be strict right..
The semicolon is optional . Sometimes it matters othertimes it does not. This is confusing.
println! statement is a macro.. what does a macro mean.</description></item><item><title>Digital Detox and Productivity</title><link>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/archive/digital-detox-and-productivity/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:44:53 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/archive/digital-detox-and-productivity/</guid><description>Think about this, if every speaker around you starts playing music but all of them are playing different songs then all of them would be noise, and none of them would be useful. As a sane person, you would close down rest of the speaker and only play the speaker that is important among them to you at the current moment. And you would want the speaker to do that well and that music to be good too.</description></item><item><title>Notes on Communication</title><link>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/archive/notes-on-communication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 19:26:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/archive/notes-on-communication/</guid><description>&lt;p>As I was watching Ajay Banga&amp;rsquo;s interview and Ayn Rand&amp;rsquo;s interview today (videos embedded at the end of article), I realized something that should be considered very important :&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They were very good at expressing their views and opinions. They were good at communicating effectively. They were communicating as effectively as they could to avoid any misunderstanding.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Steve Blank's Podcast Interview</title><link>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/archive/steve-blank/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 16:46:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/archive/steve-blank/</guid><description>&lt;p>Interesting Podcasts by Steve Blank. Please listen if you are interested to learn about Entrepreneurship.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --></description></item><item><title>Speed vs Velocity : My Personal Experience</title><link>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/archive/speed-velocity-experience/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 16:20:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/archive/speed-velocity-experience/</guid><description>Hi, I recently read an article by Shane Parrish of the Farnam Street Blog that mentioned the importance of choosing velocity over speed.
This post actually was a nice idea and I really felt that something more could be learnt from it.
I would highly recommend you to read the article linked below
[Speed vs Velocity] (https://www.fs.blog/2018/03/speed-velocity/)
I have had my own share of personal experience with this analysis of focus and would like to share it.</description></item><item><title>The Hardest Thing Ever</title><link>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/archive/the-hardest-thing-ever/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 20:22:39 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/archive/the-hardest-thing-ever/</guid><description>The hardest thing ever is to never forget your why.
the harder thing is to not get distracted.
Why are you doing what you doing? And for what , for whom.
This is hard. Other noises of your environment will make you move away from that.
Because they don&amp;rsquo;t care for your why.
There is nothing that they will gain from it.
Cheers :smiley:</description></item><item><title>Doing Things That Matter</title><link>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/archive/doing-things-that-matter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 18:14:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/archive/doing-things-that-matter/</guid><description>All of us are given approximately the same time.
Then why do some people tend to deliver better results than others?
Simply because they do things that matter the most to them and ignore the rest.
Not everything in life matters equally.
Not every decision matters equally.
To-do list is often a lie. Some tasks are more important than others.</description></item><item><title>Focus: X divided by infinity is zero</title><link>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/archive/focus/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 18:10:29 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/archive/focus/</guid><description>A small and relatively simple concept that I have learned over the last 2 years is this.
Effort or time divided into many different , unrelated areas of focus would result in a very small output where as concentrated efforts would lead to more and more output.
If a person, puts his effort into many unrelated fields, it leads to a constant state of unhappiness and confusion.
If a business sells many different varieties of products, it might find difficulty in selling their products under the same brand.</description></item><item><title>Case Studies with the Biz Doc, Mr. Thomas Ellsworth</title><link>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/archive/case-studies-tom-ellsworth/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 13:39:02 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/archive/case-studies-tom-ellsworth/</guid><description>Mr. Thomas Ellsworth is awesome.
I love the content that he produces and I eagerly wait every Friday for him to upload his videos on my favourite YouTube channel Valuetainment.
The lessons that one can get from his case studies are extremely helpful.
The whole of Valuetainment is a gold mine for any entrepreneur and would recommend anyone to watch some of their content even if they are not an entrepreneur.</description></item><item><title>Business Lesson: Employee Equity</title><link>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/archive/employee-equity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 10:28:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/archive/employee-equity/</guid><description>Business Lesson : Pay equity to employees more than investor.
First of all, I will start that I got to learn many things yesterday about equity.
Investors are important. ( Maybe ) but they are not active in the business.
Hence it makes more sense to pay equity to employees as a startup.
Of-course both investors and employees and all the stakeholders ( shareholders ) must be vested.
Vesting is an important contract.</description></item><item><title>Cost Leadership, Differentiation and Profit Models</title><link>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/archive/cost-leadership-differentiation-profit-models/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 12:50:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/archive/cost-leadership-differentiation-profit-models/</guid><description>So Today morning , All I had to do was attend class.
This class was taught to us ( Minor in Entrepreneurship ) by Srini Addepalli ( Founder, GlobalGyan ) I really enjoyed his teachings and found them to be very useful.
Here I would like to share some of my notes with you.
Cost Leadership : The company reduces the cost of the product while selling the product at the average price.</description></item><item><title>A Business is like a Farm : The Farm Analogy</title><link>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/archive/a-business-is-like-a-farm-analogy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 21:39:52 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/archive/a-business-is-like-a-farm-analogy/</guid><description>A business is just like a farm.
Infact farming is a business that is easy for most people to understand.
You have to take care of it everyday.
You have to do the hustle and reach out to your customers.
You need land for your farm ( Initial Investments )
You hire employees to take care of your farm.
You have to regularly water it.
You have to take out the weeds.</description></item><item><title>The Great Branch of Engineering Science at IITH</title><link>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/archive/engineering-science/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 20:12:22 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/archive/engineering-science/</guid><description>Hi, I am Vibhas, studying Engineering Science at IITH ( 2014 batch ). So let me introduce you to our branch.
( I am writing this down here as some of the content on official website has not been updated yet )
No other IIT has it like ours.
Although I am not going to declare it the best branch ever. But it&amp;rsquo;s quite close to that.
B.Tech. in Engineering Science, at IIT Hyderabad, is a unique program offered in India for the first time.</description></item><item><title>HungerTorrent : Food delivery system</title><link>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/archive/hungertorrent/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 00:39:54 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://vibhasgoyal.com/posts/archive/hungertorrent/</guid><description>We delivered food to IITH students and the food was delivered by the students of college itself who went to the city on their own. We then asked them to bring our orders from restaurants and in return they got heavily paid for the delivery.
We setup the website at hungertorrent.xyz ( Cheap Domain :P )
We started the program, a day after we attended AugustFest
Now the static website has been hosted at http://hungertorrent.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://vibhasgoyal.com/todo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vibhasgoyal.com/todo/</guid><description>Make the center footer wide..
Change the logo text..
Update the about page..
Make a portfolio on the front page
Upload some photos
Add referral links for linode , digital ocean ? , cred , paytm ? , amazon..!
seo optimizations and website added to google
fetch previous content and reupload it here&amp;hellip;</description></item></channel></rss>