<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>startup on VibeCoder</title><link>https://vibecoder.dev/tags/startup/</link><description>Recent content in startup on VibeCoder</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>All Copyrights Reseved. 2022 Vibhas Goyal</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 10:28:34 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vibecoder.dev/tags/startup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Business Lesson: Employee Equity</title><link>https://vibecoder.dev/posts/employee-equity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 10:28:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://vibecoder.dev/posts/employee-equity/</guid><description>Business Lesson : Pay equity to employees more than investor.
First of all, I will start that I got to learn many things yesterday about equity.
Investors are important. ( Maybe ) but they are not active in the business.
Hence it makes more sense to pay equity to employees as a startup.
Of-course both investors and employees and all the stakeholders ( shareholders ) must be vested.
Vesting is an important contract.</description><content>&lt;p>Business Lesson : Pay equity to employees more than investor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First of all, I will start that I got to learn many things yesterday about equity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Investors are important. ( Maybe ) but they are not active in the business.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hence it makes more sense to pay equity to employees as a startup.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of-course both investors and employees and all the stakeholders ( shareholders ) must be vested.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vesting is an important contract.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If it is there, then it means that the business partners and stakeholders trust each other.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s lack means that the individuals are not able to trust each other freely.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ndash;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Equity is for those who are actively working in an organization. Note the word &amp;ldquo;Active&amp;rdquo;.. Active investors, active advisors, active founders, active employees.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If the company stocks get into the hands of those who are idle. Then it acts as a hindrance to decision making.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thus vesting ensures that equity is on the hands of those who are active.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See you soon. Peace :) \m/&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>A Business is like a Farm : The Farm Analogy</title><link>https://vibecoder.dev/posts/a-business-is-like-a-farm-analogy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 21:39:52 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://vibecoder.dev/posts/a-business-is-like-a-farm-analogy/</guid><description>A business is just like a farm.
Infact farming is a business that is easy for most people to understand.
You have to take care of it everyday.
You have to do the hustle and reach out to your customers.
You need land for your farm ( Initial Investments )
You hire employees to take care of your farm.
You have to regularly water it.
You have to take out the weeds.</description><content>&lt;p>A business is just like a farm.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Infact farming is a business that is easy for most people to understand.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You have to take care of it everyday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You have to do the hustle and reach out to your customers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You need land for your farm ( Initial Investments )&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You hire employees to take care of your farm.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You have to regularly water it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You have to take out the weeds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You need to know the market demands.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You need to know when it is time to harvest your farm.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You celebrate a good harvest like a festival.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You need to be prepared for emergencies too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You will sometimes have to bootstrap your own resources and learn to manage your expenses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You also do side hustle that helps you in farming ( poultry )&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You must also be aware of your competition.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You must learn to maintain supplies and cash flow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Working on your own farm will result in more income than working in other&amp;rsquo;s farm.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You must learn to keep valuable employees employed to your farm.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You must invest in the latest technology to stay ahead.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You may live near your farm to have a better watch over it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You must buy pesticides, high yielding seeds, machinery for a better produce.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You must also know when to buy these things, for early high investment may lead to lots of debt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You will have to protect it from wild animals ( the crazy customers ) and learn to deal with them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more profits, you must learn to create a brand for your farm.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can market it like &amp;ldquo;Organic Produce&amp;rdquo; when you are not able to afford pesticides.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Simple marketing strategies like the above would come more naturally to you when you are aware of the marketplace.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At some point, you must start acquiring other farms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Building value to your customer takes time and effort.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The crops won&amp;rsquo;t grow in a day, no matter how much effort you put into it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You must become comfortable with uncertainties in your harvest.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You should be educated enough about your farm to know where to grow what seed and how to grow it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If not experienced, you must not be afraid to seek help or information from other farmers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you do finally achieve success, you might help other farmers to achieve it too.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>HungerTorrent : Food delivery system</title><link>https://vibecoder.dev/posts/hungertorrent/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 00:39:54 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://vibecoder.dev/posts/hungertorrent/</guid><description>We delivered food to IITH students and the food was delivered by the students of college itself who went to the city on their own. We then asked them to bring our orders from restaurants and in return they got heavily paid for the delivery.
We setup the website at hungertorrent.xyz ( Cheap Domain :P )
We started the program, a day after we attended AugustFest
Now the static website has been hosted at http://hungertorrent.</description><content>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>We delivered food to IITH students and the food was delivered by the students of college itself who went to the city on their own. We then asked them to bring our orders from restaurants and in return they got &lt;em>heavily&lt;/em> paid for the delivery.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>We setup the website at hungertorrent.xyz ( Cheap Domain :P )&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We started the program, a day after we attended AugustFest&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now the static website has been hosted at &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;a href="http://hungertorrent.bitballoon.com/">http://hungertorrent.bitballoon.com/&lt;/a>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The team consisted of 5 people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Team : Vibhas Goyal, Aashish Patole, Aditya Rathi, Mudit Gupta, Safwan Mahmood &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the first few days, we delivered food at an approx. delivery cost of Rs. 30/- per food item.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We took orders from Subway, Mughal and Dominos. The program was successful in 800 series of ODF Hostels. :P&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then the orders declined, excitement was over, our motivation went down, focus dissipated and soon it reached its end in Early December 2015.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>We faced harsh reality and truths for which I really must congratulate the team. To those young people who solve, rather than whine about their problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cheers for HungerTorrent. :boom: :punch:&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>