<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on VibeCoder</title><link>https://blog.vibecoder.dev/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on VibeCoder</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 18:14:05 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.vibecoder.dev/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Smoking</title><link>https://blog.vibecoder.dev/posts/smoking/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 18:14:05 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.vibecoder.dev/posts/smoking/</guid><description>Hi Guys, I have multiple addictions in life.. there has been weed , porn, games, social media scrolling.. I would say that I am a guy (26yo now) with many addictions. I like to work and have decent source of income but my free time gets consumed by these addictions a lot more than I would like them to be.
But here I wanted to post about my first ever conquer over a addiction.</description></item><item><title>Real Conversation</title><link>https://blog.vibecoder.dev/posts/real-conversation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 22:26:02 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.vibecoder.dev/posts/real-conversation/</guid><description>We live in a time where more and more conversations can be broadcasted online.
We live in a time where more real time interactions can take place in a conversation.
And yet, what we are seeing is that less of these conversations are becoming less empathetic on social media.
Nobody is willing to see the other side of things especially when there is no reason to do that.
You can easily create your own safe space on social media.</description></item><item><title>Karma</title><link>https://blog.vibecoder.dev/posts/karma/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 07:01:57 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.vibecoder.dev/posts/karma/</guid><description>I just read the karma yoga chapter of the bhagvad gita and it started to rain.
according to what I thought I read, this rain like my body and my soul, are blessings from him.
So why should one work. cause if god ( if such a thing exist ) stops working then we are all doomed for sure. if it stops to rain, we don’t get any plants, nor any animals will be able to survive.</description></item></channel></rss>