<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on VibeCoder</title><link>https://vibecoder.dev/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on VibeCoder</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vibecoder.dev/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Samsung R&amp;D Bangalore Interview Experience</title><link>https://vibecoder.dev/posts/nvim/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vibecoder.dev/posts/nvim/</guid><description>Samsung really was the worst interview experience.
One day, I suddenly get a call from a recruiter based on my profile from Naukri.com
On the call, the recruiter basically just asked me directly when I would like to have the interview.
I was initially impressed that they decided to move it fast but this feeling did not last long..
Immediately I got an invite for the interview.
I looked at it.</description></item><item><title>LeetCode 1658</title><link>https://vibecoder.dev/posts/leetcode-1658/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vibecoder.dev/posts/leetcode-1658/</guid><description>A simple problem on the first approach that I have to look at.
Let&amp;rsquo;s see this as two pointers.
One starting from the index 0 and the other index will start from len-1.
int begin = 0 ; int end = len - 1; If there is no solution we return -1
return -1; This will track the number of edits
int count = 0; The first step is to check if arr[begin] is less than arr[end],</description></item><item><title>NVIM</title><link>https://vibecoder.dev/posts/nvim/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vibecoder.dev/posts/nvim/</guid><description>Nvim is the best editor so far. But we have to configure it.
Otherwise, it&amp;rsquo;s just a text editor.
The one down side I found is that it cannot be used very effectively over ssh.
Usually the VM&amp;rsquo;s are not configured like the way nvim is done locally.
So not a good idea to use it?
Nah, still it is so smooth and fast to use it as if this is the only thing that has made editing my files as fast as my thoughts.</description></item><item><title>Keychron K8 Pro</title><link>https://vibecoder.dev/posts/keychron-k8-pro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vibecoder.dev/posts/keychron-k8-pro/</guid><description>Why a new keyboard? I brought this keyboard because I have been looking forward to owning a proper mechanical keyboard again for some time now.
The last proper keyboard I had was the ErgoDox EZ.
It was a good keyboard.
But this is even better I think.
QMK / VIA configuration. This was a bit confusing at first. It still is but I have made some changes to suit my needs.</description></item><item><title>Welcome To My Blog</title><link>https://vibecoder.dev/posts/welcome/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vibecoder.dev/posts/welcome/</guid><description>This is the start of my journey on my way to blog.
I am not a professional blogger in any way right now.
Yes, I have started blogs in the past but right now, I am finally feeling as if I am speaking to the public to express my thoughts.
I think a lot. I think this will be a good outlet for me.
I have setup auto publish using git and hosted this on github.</description></item></channel></rss>