<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Productivity on VibeCoder</title><link>https://vibecoder.dev/tags/productivity/</link><description>Recent content in Productivity on VibeCoder</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>All Copyrights Reseved. 2022 Vibhas Goyal</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 16:20:28 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vibecoder.dev/tags/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Speed vs Velocity : My Personal Experience</title><link>https://vibecoder.dev/posts/speed-velocity-experience/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 16:20:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://vibecoder.dev/posts/speed-velocity-experience/</guid><description>Hi, I recently read an article by Shane Parrish of the Farnam Street Blog that mentioned the importance of choosing velocity over speed.
This post actually was a nice idea and I really felt that something more could be learnt from it.
I would highly recommend you to read the article linked below
[Speed vs Velocity] (https://www.fs.blog/2018/03/speed-velocity/)
I have had my own share of personal experience with this analysis of focus and would like to share it.</description><content>&lt;p>Hi, I recently read an article by Shane Parrish of the Farnam Street Blog that mentioned the importance of choosing velocity over speed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This post actually was a nice idea and I really felt that something more could be learnt from it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I would highly recommend you to read the article linked below&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>[Speed vs Velocity] (&lt;a href="https://www.fs.blog/2018/03/speed-velocity/">https://www.fs.blog/2018/03/speed-velocity/&lt;/a>)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have had my own share of personal experience with this analysis of focus and would like to share it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am actually someone who is highly obsessed with increasing my efficiency / productivity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But efficiency can also achieved by doing things in a particular direction rather than trying to do tasks faster.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Think about this: &lt;em>&lt;strong>An incremental increase in speed can only be considered useful if it is in a direction that you would like to go.&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If all the directions are random then what would end up with is zero displacement even if speed of completing tasks was increased.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a programmer in college, I have various options ahead of me. Even in CSE, there are large number of fields that one can specialise in such as&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Distributed Computing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Blockchain&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Web Development&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deep Learning / Machine learning&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Compiler engineering&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Operating systems&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>And many such.. It is important to know which fields to choose and be true to it. For me personally, I was initially interested to learn about Machine Learning and did a basic course in it, but after some time I realized that the effort I was putting in learning it was not really focused academically and my grades started to fluctuate as I began to divert from my main hobby / focus within the CSE department. ( Grades can be considered an objective measure in my opinion )&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And many times, this selection comes by eliminating the things that you would not like to do or the things that you&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[Patrick Bet-David] ( //patrickbetdavid.com ) ( my personal hero ) as often said that successful people / businesses always specialise rather than generalise. The generalised behaviour always come later.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-acheive-higher-velocity">How To Acheive Higher Velocity&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Choose your direction&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Learn to say no&lt;/strong> : to things that are not aligned with your direction.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Create a systematic approach to saying no&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Thus from now on, I would like to consider this factor while taking any decision worth undertaking and I would like to take it as a challenge for myself to see what can be achieved by doing so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To requoute from the article :&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“People think focus means saying yes to the thing you’ve got to focus on. But that’s not what it means at all. It means saying no to the hundred other good ideas that there are. You have to pick carefully. I’m actually as proud of the things we haven’t done as the things I have done. Innovation is saying ‘no’ to 1,000 things.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>/- Steve Jobs&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Peace :smile:&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Doing Things That Matter</title><link>https://vibecoder.dev/posts/doing-things-that-matter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 18:14:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://vibecoder.dev/posts/doing-things-that-matter/</guid><description>All of us are given approximately the same time.
Then why do some people tend to deliver better results than others?
Simply because they do things that matter the most to them and ignore the rest.
Not everything in life matters equally.
Not every decision matters equally.
To-do list is often a lie. Some tasks are more important than others.</description><content>&lt;p>All of us are given approximately the same time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then why do some people tend to deliver better results than others?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Simply because they do things that matter the most to them and ignore the rest.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not everything in life matters equally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not every decision matters equally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To-do list is often a lie. Some tasks &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->are &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->more important than others.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Focus: X divided by infinity is zero</title><link>https://vibecoder.dev/posts/focus/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 18:10:29 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://vibecoder.dev/posts/focus/</guid><description>A small and relatively simple concept that I have learned over the last 2 years is this.
Effort or time divided into many different , unrelated areas of focus would result in a very small output where as concentrated efforts would lead to more and more output.
If a person, puts his effort into many unrelated fields, it leads to a constant state of unhappiness and confusion.
If a business sells many different varieties of products, it might find difficulty in selling their products under the same brand.</description><content>&lt;p>A small and relatively simple concept that I have learned over the last 2 years is this.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Effort or time divided into many different , unrelated areas of focus would result in a very small output where as concentrated efforts would lead to more and more output.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If a person, puts his effort into many unrelated fields, it leads to a constant state of unhappiness and confusion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If a business sells many different varieties of products, it might find difficulty in selling their products under the same brand.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Similarly, if a person consumes various kind of news simultaneously, it leads to zero output or newer forms of understanding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the exact reason why I believe that newspaper and social media overall are of net zero value to the reader if he decides to read all of it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Too much information could cause confusion?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Learning to extract the kind of information you need is your responsibility.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you do not decide to choose your own information stream, do expect others to decide it for you ( some kind of silly mainstream media or news ). And it might not be good for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Too much information spread over various topics = Zero value.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Deciding on what you want to do is important for the same.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>